General Zu
Генерал Цзу
This year you repeatedly repelled the Wutu
ты в этом году многократно отбивал нападения Уну
You are a great hero
ты великий герой
Above, by His Majesty's great fortune
Всё благодаря императорскому благословению
Below, by the soldiers' efforts
и самоотверженности воинов
There is no reason not to win
В таких условиях поражение невозможно
Last year we couldn't go north
Жаль что в прошлом году не удалось начать северный поход
It was indeed a pity
Действительно жаль
This general's return to the capital this time
Вернувшись в столицу
Is also to discuss with Your Majesty
я как раз хотел с Вашим Величеством
This matter again
снова обсудить это
The Chen family
Здесь семья Чэнь
The Xie family
семья Се
And my two sons are all here
и оба моих сына
Feel free to speak freely
Говорите свободно
What do you all
как вы
Think about this?
на это смотрите
Victory is easy to talk about
Победа дело хорошее
But what if we lose?
А если мы проиграем
Speaking of defeat before even fighting
Ещё не началось а ты уже поражение предрекаешь
You've been in the capital so long
В столице
Your bones have gone soft
совсем расслабился
Want to be the Wutu's sons
Хочешь сыном у Уну сделаться
Discuss matters, just discuss matters
Говори по делу
Don't ramble on here
Хватит придираться
Father
Отец
Your son believes
я считаю
We should go north
что нужно начать северный поход
But not right now
Но не прямо сейчас
After all
По сути
The court has no money
в казне пусто
The people have no money either
у народа тоже нет денег
If we fight this war now
Если начать войну сейчас
How can people survive?
как людям выжить
Then where's the money?
А деньгито где
This money isn't in the people's hands
Ни у народа
Nor in the court's treasury
ни в казне
Where did the money go?
а где же они
Prince of Ning
Господин Нинван
Don't you have anything to say?
вам нечего сказать
Boy
Мальчишка
You must be very careful with your words
поосторожнее с языком
It's fine
Всё нормально
Father said
Отец сам разрешил
Today we can
говорить
Speak freely
откровенно
But second brother
А вот ты братец
You should also give your opinion
пора бы и позицию свою обозначить